# Agustin Guerra

888-858-6716 | agustinguerra@ufl.edu | LinkedIn | Website

# Professional Profile

Highly motivated engineering professional with 5+ years of experience in the transportation industry. Committed to providing high-quality service focusing on innovation, safety, sustainability, operational performance, diversity, equity, and inclusion. Currently pursuing a PhD degree in Civil Engineering.

#### **EDUCATION**

PhD candidate in Civil Engineering

University of Florida, GPA: 3.66

MS in Civil Engineering University of Kansas, GPA: 3.89

BS in Civil Engineering

Universidad Tecnologica de Panama

Aug. 2019 – Expected May 2023

Gainesville, FL

 $Aug.\ 2017-May\ 2019$ 

Lawrence, KS

Mar. 2008 - May 2013

Panama, PA

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Expertise: Transportation Engineering, Statistical Analysis, Operation Research, Machine Learning

Languages: Python (Proficient), R (Intermediate)

Software: VISSIM, HCS, AutoCAD Civil 3D, Infraworks, Slide-Rockscience

Developer Tools: Github, Visual Studio

Libraries: Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, CPLEX

# EXPERIENCE

WSP

# Graduate Research Assistant

Aug. 2019 – Present

Gainesville, FL

University of Florida

- Develop optimization algorithms in Python for arterials considering automated-vehicles capabilities
- $\bullet$  Assist in the implementation of optimization algorithm for isolated intersections
- Facilitated the coordination of project activities to meet deadlines
- Explained traffic flow theory assignments to students

### Highway & Traffic Consultant

May 2019 - Aug. 2019

Panama

- Provided safety assessment for roadways, interchanges, and intersections
- Developed geometric design proposals
- Conducted earthwork estimation for highway projects

## Highway Engineer

Nov. 2012 - Aug. 2017

Panama

Louis Berger

- Developed geometric designs for proposal and as-built drawings for highway projects. Project portfolio comprises several projects in the Latin American region (Panama, Colombia, Honduras, and Peru) adding up to \$3 billion in construction amount
- Coordinated with different departments (geotechnical, hydraulic, and pavement) to meet deadlines
- Created digital model terrain for highway projects
- Verified slope stability analysis using the Slide-Rockscience software
- Supervised and mentored drafter team with 4 people

engagement activities between industry professionals and students

## Leadership/Involvement

<b>Volunteer at the Young Member Council</b> : Currently develop a website for the YMC - S&R	2022 – Present
Co-founder of the IEEE-ITS Student Chapter: Currently leading the efforts to establish an IEEE Student Chapter focused on ITS	2022 – Present
ITE University Chapter Vice President: Coordinated student seminars and $\underline{\text{ITE}}$ activities	2021 - 2022
Student Representative at the UFTI Internal Steering Committee: Promoted	2020 - 2022

# Fellowships & Awards

ITS Florida Anne Brewer Academic Scholarships: Awarded by the ITS Florida Chapter	2022
Fulbright Fellowship: Awarded by the U.S Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs	2017
Global Best Project: Awarded by the ENR for the Coastal Beltway project in Panama	2015
Relevant Projects	
4th Bridge over the Panama Canal   Panama	2019
<ul> <li>Provided visibility and safety assessment for intersections and roadways</li> </ul>	
• Developed geometric design alternatives for interchanges	
• Construction cost: \$1.2 billions	
Corredor Panama Norte   Panama	2016
• Played a major role in the coordination of the project	
<ul> <li>Developed design drawings and calculations including 3D models of roadways, roundabouts, and int</li> <li>Provided earthworks estimation</li> </ul>	terchanges
Perimetral Oriental de Bogota   Colombia	2015
• Coordinated with other departments (geotechnical, hydraulic, surveying) to meet deadlines	
• Developed design drawings and calculations including 3D models of roadways, intersections, and int	erchanges
• Trained and supervised drafter team	
• Construction cost: \$428.0 millions	
Panamerican Highway Widening Santiago -Vigui   Panama	2014
• Provided design alternatives including 3D models and drawings for intersections	
• Analyzed the slope stability of critical sections	
• Construction cost: \$340.0 millions	
Corredor Turistico La Barca – El Progreso – Tela   Honduras	2014
<ul> <li>Conceived design drawings for roundabouts and urban sections including sidewalks, and bus-stops</li> <li>Provided traffic signs drawings using the MUTCD and local guidelines</li> </ul>	
• Construction cost: \$120.0 millions	
Slope Stabilization Studies 53 km   Panama	2014
• Interpreted the slope stability analysis results	2014
• Examined ground improvement alternatives	
• Construction cost: \$0.4 millions	
Amador Causeway Widening   Panama	2014
• Assisted with the geometric design of roundabouts	
• Participated in the creation of the digital terrain model	
<ul> <li>Assisted with the modeling of critical sections for embankments stability analysis</li> </ul>	
• Construction cost: \$95.0 millions	
Coastal Beltway   Panama	2012
• Developed design drawings for roadways including roundabouts, marine viaducts, and interchanges	
• Construction cost: \$ 45 millions	
Professional Societies	
<u>IEEE</u> : Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers	2022 - Present
ASCE: American Society of Civil Engineers	2022 - Present
<u>ITE</u> : Institute of Transportation Engineers	2019 – Present
References	
Lily Elefteriadou, PhD: Barbara Goldsby Professor, University of Florida el	lefter@ce.ufl.edu

Lily Elefteriadou, PhD: Barbara Goldsby Professor, University of Florida Aurora Izquierdo: Civil Structural Engineer II, WSP Juliana Canas: Senior Advisor, First Climate Julio Aysa: Env./Social and Governance Lead Officer, IDB

elefter@ce.ufl.edu Aurora.Izquierdo@wsp.com juliana.canas-vanegas@firstclimate.com jaysa71@yahoo.com.mx